지난 줄거리입니다
Previously:
내가 많이 좋아하는 여자가 있어
There's this woman that I like a lot.
그런데 그게 복잡해
But it's complicated.
오랫동안 만나온 남자가 있거든
She was with this other guy
for a long time.
그 남자와는 맞설 수가 없어
우린 친구거든
I could never do that to the guy.
We're friends.
그 옛날 애인이란 남자
괜찮은 친구야?
So this guy she used to go out with,
is he a good guy?
최고지
The best.
- 그럼 가서 얘기해
- 모르겠어
-Then talk to him.
-I don't know.
그 여자를 좋아한다면 시도해봐
It's worth finding out,
if you like her.
좋아해, 아주 많이
I do, so much.
그 여자 생각만 해, 잠도 못 자고...
I can't stop thinking about her.
I can't sleep..
그렇다면 더 망설일 이유가 없어
You know what?
You have to go for it.
이런 기회가 자주 올 것 같아?
밀고 나가는 거야
How often does this happen to you?
You owe it to yourself.
레이첼이야
It's Rachel.
방금 레이첼이랬어?
I'm sorry, did you just say
it's Rachel?
그래
Yes.
레이첼을 좋아한다구?
You like Rachel?
그래, 내가 레이첼을 좋아해
Yes. I like Rachel.
레이첼!?
Rachel?!
그래, 근데 저기 말야
Yeah. Okay, but look, you know..
내가 또 누굴
좋아하는지 알아? 너야
You know who else I like? You.
주어 동사가 빠졌네
내가 널 좋아해
And it doesn't get said enough.
I like you, Ross.
- 그 레이첼 말야?
- 신경 쓸 거 없어
-"Rachel" Rachel?
-It's not a big deal.
신경 쓸 거 없다구?
미안한데 난 도무지...
It's not a big deal?
I'm sorry, I just..
그럼 방금 얘기한 건 다 뭐야?
What about the stuff you said?
레이첼 생각뿐이라고 한 건?
잠을 못 잘 정도라고?
How you can't stop thinking about her?
How you can't sleep?
난 배우잖아
I'm an actor, you know?
배우들은 원래 오버를 잘한다구
As a group, we tend to be
overdramatic.
내 아일 임신하고 있는 레이첼?
Rachel-who's-carrying-my-baby Rachel?
이럼 안 된다는 거 알아, 알겠어?
I know it's bad.
And I know it's wrong, okay?
아무 일도 일어나지 않을 거라구
It's not like anything's
ever gonna happen.
그냥 감정일 뿐이야
사라질 거라구
These are just feelings.
They'll go away.
그만 가야겠어
You know, I gotta go.
잠깐만, 로스...
Hey, Ross..
난 도대체가 무슨...
레이첼?
You know, I just have one--
Rachel?!
레이첼?
프렌즈 시즌 8
'조이의 고백'
발길질을 하고 있어
Okay, she's kicking.
뱃속에서 잘도 크네
She's growing inside you.
- 세게 걷어찼어
- 이런 어린 애한테 차이다니
-That was a big one.
-That's the youngest girl to reject me.
- 안녕!
- 어서 와
-You guys!
-Hey there.
너희들 천생연분이란 걸 믿어?
Let me ask you.
Do you believe in soul mates?
물론이지
Oh, yes, I do.
누구한테나 제 짝이라는 게 있어
There's one person out there
for everyone.
그 짝을 어떻게 찾냐구?
찾는 걸 그만두면 돼
You know how you find him?
Stop looking.
그래서 난 러셀 크로우
찾는 걸 그만뒀어
I've stopped looking
for Russell Crowe.
러셀이 날 찾을 거야
He'll find me.
넌?
And you?
안 믿어, 다른 사람에 비해
죽이 더 잘 맞는 사람이 있을 뿐
No. I believe that certain people
are more suited for each other, but..
- 천생연분? 그런 건 없어
- 좋아
-Soul mates? I don't think they exist.
-Good.
- 왜?
- 어제 모니카의 천생연분을 만났어
-Why?
-Well, last night, I met Monica's.
뭐?
What?
어제 나랑 데이트한 남자가
모니카의 천생연분 이더라니까
I had a date with this guy.
I swear he's her other half.
모니카한테 나보다 더
잘 맞는 사람이 있을 것 같아?
You don't think there's somebody
better suited for Monica than me?
어떻게 생겼는데?
Well, what's he like?
- 키가 크고 머리는 갈색이야
- 당연하지
-He's tall. He has brown hair.
-Of course.
키가 크고 머린 나랑 비슷하다구?
세상 참 넒기도 해라!
A tall guy with hair similar to mine?
Oh, unknowable universe!
- 요식업에 종사해
- 그래야지, 연상이야?
-He works with food.
-Oh, sure. Older?
- 그럼, 영국인이야
- 물어보려던 참이었어!
-Obviously. And he's British.
-I was just gonna ask!
아주 똑똑하고 점잖고
자신감이 넘치는 사람이야
And he's so centered,
and mature and confident.
모니카랑 못 만났다니 안됐네
It's so sad they never met.
모니카의 남편이 그 얘길
못 들어서 다행이야
Luckily, the guy she settled for
can't hear you.
미안해, 내가 잘못 알았는지도 몰라
Oh, I'm so sorry.
Maybe I'm wrong.
또 만나기로 했으니까
좀더 알아볼게
We're going out again.
I'll find out more.
모니카의 천생연분과
데이트를 한다구?
He's meant for her,
and you're gonna date him?
내 천생연분은 아니지만
나도 먹어야 살지
He may not be my soul mate,
but a girl's gotta eat.
레이첼?
Rachel?!
재그에 출연했는지는 몰랐네
I didn't know Joey was on JAG.
- 오빠
- 어서 와
-Hey.
조이랑 얘길 했어
오빠가 어쩐지 보려고
I talked to Joey.
I wanted to see you.
믿을 수가 없어, 조이랑 레이첼?
I still can't believe it.
Joey and Rachel?
우리가 연애하는 거랑 똑같잖아
It's like you and me going out,
only weirder.
상처 받은 건 아는데
I know you're hurting..
그런 말 마
but don't say that again.
둘이 결혼하면 어떡해?
조이가 내 아이 계부가 되는 거야
What if they marry?
He'd be the stepfather of my child.
그런 걱정은 하지 마
You don't need to worry.
조이는 레이첼한테 고백 안해
He'll never tell her how he feels.
한다고 해도 레이첼이
어떻게 나올지도 모르고
If he did, you don't know
how she'd react.
그래, 여자들이 조이 싫어하더라
걔 아직 숫총각일 걸
Sure, women never like Joey.
I think he's a virgin.
- 조이는 지금 그런 생각 안해
- 그래?
-He isn't thinking about going for her.
-He's not?
오빠가 어떤지만 염려하고 있다구
All he's thinking about
is how you're taking this.
완전히 초조해선
버몬트로 이사를 가겠대
It's freaking him out.
He wants to move to Vermont.
- 왜?
- 미국을 떠나고 싶대
-Why?
-He wants to leave the country.
오빠가 미워하는 줄 알아
He thinks you hate him.
미워해?
Hate him?
그렇지 않아
No, I don't hate him.
그냥... 레이첼이잖아
It's just, it's Rachel. You know?
상상도 못할 정도로 힘들겠지만
I can't even imagine how hard
this must be for you..
이 일로 조이를 잃진 마
but I don't want you
to lose Joey over it.
둘이 아직 친구인지 알고 싶어해
Right now, he needs to know
that you're still his friend.
알았어, 가서 얘기할게
Okay, I'll talk to him.
서둘러
I'd do it soon.
조이가 버몬트 돈으로
환전하는 법을 묻더라구
He just asked me how to convert
his dollars into Vermont money.
- 안녕!
- 안녕
-Hi!
-Hi.
- 챈들러, 모니카, 여긴 돈이야
- 안녕하세요
-Chandler, Monica, this is Don.
-Hello.
반갑습니다, 안녕하세요?
Hello, nice to meet you.
How are you?
천생연분
Soul mate.
- 둘이 뭐 했어요?
- 아드리아티카에서 점심 했는데
-What are you guys doing?
-We had lunch at Adriatica.
- 웬 자연 건조 토마토예요?
- 알아요! 지금이 1985년인가?
-What's with the sun-dried tomatoes?
-I know! Is this 1985?
- 나도 그 말했는데! 묘하잖아요?
- 뭐 별로요
-That's what I said! Isn't it strange?
-Not really.
자연 건조 토마토가 왜요?
What's wrong with sun-dried tomatoes?
바비큐 치킨 피자에 넣은?
On a barbecued-chicken pizza?
아냐?
No?
- 또 어떤 식당 좋아해요?
- 27번과 7번 코너의 옥타비오요
-What restaurants do you like?
-Octavio. 27-and-7.
- 알레산드로스도 좋아요
- 어머! 내가 거기 요리사예요!
-There's this place, Alessandro's.
-Oh, my God! I'm the chef!
설마! 당신 음식은 환상적이에요!
You're kidding!
Your food is fantastic!
당신 메뉴에 대해 얘기해요
커피 마실 사람?
I want to talk about your menu.
Anyone want coffee?
내 얘기한다는데 나도 같이 가요
If you're talking about me,
I'll go with you.
난 모카치노
I'll have a mocha-ccino.
뭐 하는 거야?
What are you doing?
두 사람이 여기 있는 줄 몰랐어
I swear, I didn't know you guys
would be here.
천생연분 안 믿는다며? 그러니...
You don't believe in soul mates, so..
잘생긴 남자들이
모니카한테 반하는 건 믿어
I believe in handsome strangers
who hit on my wife.
둘이 아무리 천생연분 이라 해도
별 일 안 생길 테니 걱정 마
Just because I think they're soul mates
doesn't mean anything'll happen.
피비? 잘했어
Phoebe? Good work.
멋져, 내 맘에 쏙 들어
He's great. I love him.
걱정 마, 너도 딴 사람 생길 거야
Don't worry, we'll find you
someone else.
날 때리러 왔대도 이해해
난 맞아도 싸니까
I understand if you came by to hit me.
I deserve it.
때리러 온 거 아냐
No, I don't want to hit you.
그럼 발로 차려고?
What, then? Kick me?
아니
No.
깨물게?
Bite me?
그러려고 온 거 아냐
I don't want to do anything to you.
그냥 너한테 화 안났다는 거랑
I just want to say I'm not
mad at you..
널 미워하지 않는단 말 하려고
and that I certainly
do not hate you.
그 말하러 왔어
I just came here to say that.
잠깐만, 로스
Hey, wait, Ross?
들어와서 맥주라도 마실래?
You wanna come in
for a beer or something?
그래
Yeah, sure.
맥주 사왔어?
You got any beer?
레이첼이 남기고 간
멜론 드링크뿐이야
All I got is melon stuff
that Rachel left.
좋아
Okay.
이것만은 알아줘
You need to understand something.
레이첼한테 접근하는 일은
없을 거야, 알겠어?
I am never gonna act
on this Rachel thing, okay?
우리 우정을 위태롭게
할 만한 일은 안 한다구
I wouldn't do anything to jeopardize
my friendship with you.
고마워
Thank you.
어쨌든...
Anyway, it'll just..
맘 정리하려면 시간은 걸릴 거야
It'll take me a while to get over her.
어떻게 할지 모르겠어
사랑에 빠져보긴 처음이라...
I'm not sure how to do that.
I've never been in love, so..
뭐?
What?
사랑한다구?
You're in love with her?
- 그래, 알고 있는 줄 알았어
- 아니
-Yeah. I thought you knew that.
-No.
나도 이런 감정이 부담스러워
Look, if it helps, I don't want
to feel this way, honest.
계속 다짐한다구
'마음을 정리해야 돼'
I just keep thinking,
"I'll get over this," you know?
하지만 그럴수록 점점 심해져
But it just keeps getting harder.
어떻게 해야 할지를 모르겠어
I don't know what to do, you know?
어떡하지?
What do I do?
- 레이첼한테 네 감정을 고백해
- 이거 마시고 취했구나
-You need to tell her how you feel.
-That's the green stuff talking.
진심이야
레이첼의 맘을 알아보라구
I'm serious.
You need to find out where she is.
네 맘과 같지 않다면
정리도 더 쉬워지잖아
If she's not where you are,
you can start to move on.
만약... 꼭 그렇단 건 아니지만...
But what if,
and I'm not saying she will be..
만약 네 맘과 같다면
If she is where you are..
내 기분 때문에
둘을 방해해선 안 되겠지
then my feeling weird
shouldn't stand in the way.
- 진심이야?
- 그래
-Are you sure?
-Yeah.
레이첼이 누굴 만나게 된다면
If she ends up with somebody else..
솔직히 너만한 상대도 없잖아
the truth is,
she couldn't find a better guy.
고마워
Hey, thanks.
- 언제 얘기할 거야?
- 맙소사, 얘기해야 되는구나
-So when are you gonna talk to her?
-Oh, my God. I have to tell her.
생각 안해봤어, 뭐라고 말하지?
I haven't thought about it.
What should I say?
이해는 하는데 나 흥분시키지 마
I'm understanding,
but let's not get carried away.
뭐라고 하지?
What am I gonna say?
그러게 말야
Yeah, tell me about it.
포도주에서 치즈 수입 쪽으로
초점을 옮기고 있죠
I'm phasing out the wine importing
and focusing more on the cheese.
치즈요?
Cheese, you say?
거 참 냄새 나는 일이네
안 그래요, 돈?
That's some
pretty smelly work, huh, Don?
- 뭐라구요?
- 치즈요, 냄새 나잖아요
-Excuse me?
-Cheese. It's smelly.
당신도 냄새가 좀 고약하겠어요
You must smell a lot of the time too.
별로요, 사실 치즈는
냄새가 고약할수록 맛있죠
Not really. But with cheese,
I think the smellier, the better.
맞아요! 챈들러는 치즈를 싫어해서
블루 치즈는 사놓지도 못하게 해요
Me too! Chandler hates it.
I can't have blue cheese in the house.
근데도 이혼 안 했어요?
And you're still married to him?
프랑스에 가서 치즈랑 빵만
먹고 살았으면 좋겠어요
I would like to go to France and eat
nothing but bread and cheese.
빵은 필요 없어, 치즈만요
Not even bread. Just cheese.
아냐, 빵 먹을래
No, I want the bread.
페이스트리랑
And pastries.
파테랑
And pate.
마약한 거 아니고
전에 뚱뚱했었거든요
I'm really not high.
I just used to be fat.
르와 밸리에 빌라가 있어요
프랑스에 오면 거기서 묵어요
I have a villa in the Loire Valley
you can stay in.
치즈로 만든 건가요?
Is it made of cheese?
아뇨, 치즈로 만든 집이라
너무 멋있지 않아요?
No. A house made of cheese,
wouldn't that be incredible?
- 당장에라도 옮겨요!
- 잘났어!
-I'd move in tomorrow!
-Oh, come on!
- 방금 들었어?
- 미안해
-Listen to this!
-I'm so sorry.
- 어떻게 하지?
- 치즈로 만든 집이 좋대잖아
-What do we do?
-They both want a house of cheese.
그런 걸 어떻게 말려
I don't know how you fight that.
좋아, 난 할 수 있어
내 감정을 말하는 거야
Okay, okay. I can do this.
I can tell her how I feel.
가슴 쫙 펴고
Okay, stand up straight.
심호흡 하고
Take a couple deep breaths.
당당하게
Look confident.
조이? 웬일이야?
Joey? What's up?
그냥 좀 할 얘기가 있어 들렀어
I came by because
I want to talk to you about something.
뭔데?
What's up?
복도에서? 우리가 뭐 동물이야?
Here, in the hall?
What are we, animals?
회의에 늦었어
빨리 끝내면 안 될까?
I'm late for a meeting.
Could you make it quick?
좋아, 할 말이 뭐냐면...
I just came by to tell you that..
오늘 밤 나랑 같이 저녁 먹자고
I want to have dinner with you.
알았어, 어디서 만날 건지
정해서 연락해 줘
Sure. Just tell me where to meet you.
좋아, 잘됐어
Okay. That's good.
맘의 준비를 할 시간을 벌었잖아
That gives you a couple of hours
to prepare.
노크 좀 하면 덧나요?
Don't you people ever knock?
돈과 피비를 초대할까 봐
재밌을 것 같지 않아?
I'd like to have Don and Phoebe over.
Wouldn't that be nice?
좋아, 초대해
Sure. Set it up.
난 인사란이나 훑어보고 있을게
I'll just be browsing
through the personals.
괜찮아? 좀 이상하네
Are you okay?
You're acting weird.
그럼, 괜찮아, 완벽하진 않지만
Yeah. Fine. Not perfect.
견딜 만해
But good enough.
나 참, 왜 그래?
Jeez, what's with you?
잠깐만, 방금 '치즈'랬어?
I'm sorry, did you say "cheese"?
- 왜 그래?
- 피비 말이 둘이 천생연분 이래
-What's going on?
-Phoebe says you and Don are soul mates.
그걸 믿는 건 아니지만
둘이 죽이 너무 잘 맞잖아
I don't believe in that,
but you two get along.
돈이랑 같이 치즈로 만든 집에서
살고 싶다고 해도 안 붙잡을 거야
I'll step aside if you wanna go with
Don and live in a house of cheese.
- 천생연분을 안 믿어?
- 안 믿어, 토마토는 믿을 걸
-You don't believe in soul mates?
-No, but I'm sure "tomahtoes" does.
나도 그런 거 안 믿어
I don't believe in soul mates, either.
- 정말?
- 그래
-You don't?
-Nope.
우린 천생연분 이라 만난 게 아냐
We weren't destined
to end up together.
서로 사랑하고 노력했기 때문이지
We fell in love and work hard
at our relationship.
언젠간 진짜 노력할 거야
Some days we work really hard.
그럼 치즈로 만든 집으로
이사 가는 거 아니지?
So you don't want to live with Don
in a cheese house?
아니, 생각해 봤는데
청소하기 얼마나 힘든 줄 알아?
No, I've had second thoughts.
Do you know how hard it'd be to clean?
- 사랑해
- 알아
-I love you.
-I know.
오늘 밤 우리 외식해
I'm gonna take you out to dinner.
고추 파퍼스를 잘 만드는 식당을
한 군데 알아냈거든
I found this place that makes
the greatest jalapeno poppers.
싫어? 진짜 맛있는데
No? They taste so good.
챈들러가 내 배를
만질 때마다 그런다니까
It happens whenever Chandler
touches my stomach.
애가 챈들러를 안 좋아하나 봐
I'm worried the baby won't like him.
- 괜찮아?
- 응, 그럼
-Are you okay?
-Yeah, sure.
저기 말야...
Look, the reason..
여기 덥지 않아?
Is it hot in here?
난 괜찮은데 스웨터를 벗지 그래?
Why don't you take off your sweater?
여기 고급 식당이야
This is a nice place..
티셔츠에 캘빈이 홉스한테
그러는 게 그려져 있단 말야
and my T-shirt has a picture
of Calvin doing Hobbes.
맙소사, 정말이야? 좀 봐도 돼?
Oh, my God, really? Can I see it?
그럼
Yeah, sure.
홉스가 보면 열 받겠네
I wouldn't think Hobbes
would like that so much.
우리가 안 지 얼마나 됐지?
How long have we known each other?
7, 8...
Seven, eight..
8년
Eight years. Wow.
오래됐네
A long time.
지난 몇 주 동안, 난...
But over the past few weeks, I..
좋아요! 늦어서 죄송합니다
손님이 꽉 차서 말이죠
Okay! Sorry about the wait,
but it is mega-jammed in here.
오늘밤 특선은...
Our specials tonight..
- 조금 있다 오겠어요?
- 그러죠
-Could you give us a second?
-Sure.
조금 있다 왔어요!
Second's up!
여기선 안통하네
Not that kind of table.
계속해 봐
So you were saying?
까먹었어
I'm not sure.
우리가 안 지 얼마나 됐냐고 해서
내가 8년이라고 했고
You asked how long we knew each other,
and I said eight years.
그러다 웨이터가 와서
자기 팁을 반으로 깎아먹었고
Then the waiter came over
and cut his tip in half..
여기까지 했어
and now here we are.
그래, 그러네
Yeah. Here we are.
나 널 사랑하는 것 같아
I think I'm falling in love with you.
뭐?
What?
널 사랑해
I'm falling in love with you.
누구한테 말하는 거야?
Who are you talking to?
농담이구나
Oh, you're kidding. It's a joke.
재밌다, 재밌었어!
Funny. It's funny!
이해가 안 돼
I don't get it.
그래
Okay.
와
Wow.
오늘 특선은...
Okay, so the specials are..
너가...
Are you..?
어떻게...
How did..?
언제?
When?
그게 중요해?
Does it really matter?
와, 와
Wow. Wow.
여기 덥다
It is hot in here.
갑작스러운 거 알아
I know this is a lot.
지금 당장은 아무 말 안 해도 돼
You don't have to say anything.
시간을 갖고 천천히 생각해 봐
You take as much time as you need.
무슨 말 좀 해
Okay, you gotta say something.
조이, 널 무척 사랑해
Joey, I love you so much.
- 하지만...
- 하지만
-But..
-But.
조이?
Joey?
그래, 난...
Right. Hey, that's..
난 괜찮아
That's okay. That's fine.
이럴 거라고 예상을 했었거든
It's pretty much what I was expecting.
신경 쓰지 마, 알았어?
It's no big deal, all right?
- 나 먼저 갈게
- 안 돼, 이러고 가면 어쩌라고
-I think I'm gonna go.
-Please don't leave like this.
임신한 여자한테 이러면 안 돼!
You can't do this to a pregnant woman!
그러지 마
Don't start doing that.
울지 마, 안 그럼 나도 눈물이...
You can't do that,
because you're gonna make me..
결국 터졌군!
Oh, there we go!
- 안아 줄래?
- 그럼
-Can I?
-Sure.
조이, 난 정말 잃고 싶지...
Oh, Joey. I don't want to lose..
레이첼
Hey, hey.
그런 일 없어, 알겠어? 절대로
You can't, okay? Ever.
정말 미안해
I'm so sorry.
미안하단 말 하지 마
Please don't be sorry.
알았어? 그런 말 마
Okay? Don't be sorry.
그냥 농담한 거야
You know, I was only kidding.
알아, 깜박 속았어
Yeah, that was a real good one.
- 네 담당이야?
- 그래
-Is this your table?
-Yeah.
- 밤 새겠네
- 그러게 말야
-You'll be here all night.
-I know.
특선 메뉴도 아직 못 읽어줬어
I haven't even read the specials.
왜 저래?
What's the matter?
모르겠어, 둘 중 하나가 죽나 봐
I don't know.
I think maybe one of them is dying.
여자 쪽이었으면 좋겠어
I kind of hope it's the girl.
저 남자 너무 귀엽잖아!
The guy is really cute!